Contact

Addis Ababa , +251910485824 (Mobile) bekalutadele@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/bekalu-tadele (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Data Science
Python (Programming Language)
Microsoft Azure

Languages

Amharic

English Us

Certifications

Analyzing and Visualizing Data in Looker

SQL for Data science

Introduction to Data Engineering

Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)

Data Science Orientation

Publications

Detection and classification of COVID-19 disease from X-ray images using convolutional neural networks and histogram of oriented gradients

Ethiopian sign language recognition using deep convolutional neural network

Comparative Analysis of Deep Learning Models for Aspect Level Amharic News Sentiment Analysis

Bekalu Tadele

Data Engineer at Excellerent Solutions
Addis Ababa

Summary

I am a passionate and driven data engineer and data analyst, always striving towards achieving and exceeding my goals. works on different data visualization and analytics tools, including Tableau Prep Builder, Tableau Desktop, Tableau Server, Looker, and Power Bi. I have experience of performing data engineering ETL operations using Python, SQL, Snowflake, Five Tran, Azure, GCP, and AWS. I have experience with Google Big Query, PostgreSQL, and RDS databases; additionally, Apache Airflow data streaming and task scheduling tools. designing pipelines for both structured and unstructured data. Extensive research experience in computer vision, machine learning, sentiment analysis, deep learning, and data analysis, as well as a strong educational background in IT (BSc and MSc).

Experience

Excellerent Solutions
Data Engineer
November 2021 - Present (7 months)
Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Haramaya University
Senior Lecturer
March 2017 - Present (5 years 3 months)
Dire Dawa, Ethiopia

Addis Ababa Center of Comptencey
Junior Database Expert
February 2016 - July 2017 (1 year 6 months)
Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

radio ribaba, Etinopi

Education

Haramaya University

Bachelor of Science - BSc, Information Technology · (November 2012 - June 2015)

University of Gondar

Master of Science - MSc, Information Technology · (October 2018 - September 2020)